Hello everyone, I am Pasquale Perrotta, and this is the second module of V-Cycle Explanation.
As all the lessons that I'm recording, the lesson will start just showing you the references, okay?
So, here we have my reference, okay, name and surname, plus the, sorry, name and last name,
and the email address, which is pasquale.perrotta, head sign kineton.it.
I like to start in this way, because whenever you have, in case you have doubts after this explanation,
or even after the explanation of the first module of the V-Cycle, and you have some curiosities, doubts, problems, whatever,
you know, you can write an email to that, yeah, the email shown over there, or simply you can send me a message in chat.
The aim of today's video recording is to go deeper into details about V-Cycle Explanation that you have already watched and received with the other video,
V-Cycle Part 1. Why is this needed? This is needed because, because of, basically, one reason.
In the, in the past video recording, what you have seen, basically, it's a simplified version of the V-Cycle,
which looks like something like this, okay, which looks like this.
I will not explain the V-Cycle again, using this scheme, because you have already had this explanation in the other video.
So, I will be very fast on this slide, and then we will go through the reason why I'm recording this,
let's say, deeper explanation about the V-Cycle.
So, you have already seen this, so, as you know, the first and most important thing is the software requirements, okay?
Everything starts from requirements.
So, please, you will listen me or other people saying this many times.
The requirements are the starting point for all the activities that we are going to do, okay?
So, whatever you're doing, if you're working on the diagnosis, if you're working on network,
if you're working in the car, the child, wherever you are working,
the first input of the activities is always the requirements.
Why so?
Requirements are extremely important because we need a set of instructions that then have to be implemented in the software.
So, here we have software requirements.
Basically, these are documents, okay?
Like Word documents, PDF documents, you know, textual documents, okay?
These documents will, once they're prepared, let's say, they are shared to the software development team
that will create an architecture of the software.
We'll start to deeper these software architectures, starting to, let's say, think about big blocks
that should, let's say, be part of the software itself.
So, they will divide software in domains, but, yeah, we will not go into details now about that.
And finally, the software developer team will write the actual code, okay?
This will not be the aim of this lesson and probably of this learning phase.
If you're following a validation program, we will not go through the phases of software architecture,
software configuration, and software construction.
But why this is important?
This is important because the software developers will consider as an input software requirements.
And then, once the software is ready, this software is delivered to the testing team
that will start at the unit test phase, the integration test phase, and the functional test phase.
There will be other lessons, probably the lessons related to the software verification,
where we will enter every single block that we see here on the right side,
the unit test, the integration test, and functional test.
We will add some more details, but for the sake of this lesson, we will not enter these blocks.
I want to just remind what the V-cycle looks like and add, in addition, that apart from the purple V that we see here,
there are also gray blocks.
These are functional test design, integration test design, and unit test design.
So, basically, once we have the requirements, once we have software architecture or software design,
we can start to develop some test cases, so we can prepare the tests that we have to do,
starting to write them, and once we actually have the software,
or the integrated hardware in the system, for example, system hardware in the loop,
where we have more than one electronic control unit,
or simply we have a car where we can perform a functional test,
we can start to prepare all the tests,
and once we have the bench to open the cars, we can actually perform the tests.
Okay.
So, this is a fast explanation about the V-cycle,
and probably in the first module, something like this was already explained,
and this V-cycle repeats itself in many phases of the project.
So, about the design, about the requirements, about the software development,
and stuff like this.
Okay.
So, this V-cycle will repeat itself many times.
We finally get to the point of this second module.
The point of this second module is to say,
okay, this is wonderful.
I mean, this is very clear, easy to understand.
This is the process.
Great.
Question.
How do we use this V-cycle in a real case scenario?
Actually, I go to work.
I sit on my chair in front of the computer.
How?
The V-cycle is going to affect my activities.
So, the aim of this second module is to bring everything that you have seen
in the previous presentation that is, let's say, general,
and try to place this V-cycle on a real project.
This is a project I was working on, and of course, I will not mention it for copyrights reasons,
but this is actually a real case scenario I was working on,
and we will see how all that we have said about the V-cycle actually applies also on a real case scenario.
So, let's move to this other slide.
You will not get this presentation yet because this is part of a bigger presentation
that will arrive later in the validation learning and training program.
But you can, you know, have a look at the video and then, let's say, use it to study.
Let's just see something.
Okay, there is a little spoiler here, but then, yeah, let's see what it is.
So, what is that?
I imagine that that's what you ask yourself once you have seen the first video,
and then you received the exercise after the first video.
In front of this slide, probably everyone would have asked himself or herself,
okay, what am I supposed to do with this drawing?
What are all these dots?
What are this stuff?
This is an intended shock, let's say, that we provide you
because we want first to test how you react from the, let's say, didactical point of view
that is the first module of this, of this, yeah, VooCycle topic
and see what you're able to understand about something like this
and how you would place the VooCycle here on a real case scenario.
Of course, you are going to watch this video right after you have tried
at least once or twice or three times to resolve the exercise, okay?
Not everything is answerable from the exercise without this explanation,
but part of it, it is.
So, before you move on, please make sure that you have already shared
one of your solutions of the exercise before this one will,
this explanation will probably reply to all the questions
that are asked for the VooCycle exercise.
So, let's see.
As you can imagine, this is a, yeah, of course,
looking at the top part of the presentation,
here we see a timeline, okay?
What we really care about starts in 2020 and 2022.
So, the lifespan of this project is 2020 to 2022.
Let's start from the left part.
So, the left part is the, let's say, first moments of a project, okay?
And while we move on the right side of this slide,
we are advancing in time.
That means that the project is advancing as well,
or at least it's supposed to advance.
So, the maturity of the project is advancing.
So, as you see here, in the top left part of the slide,
there is the program approval.
Program approval is something that really happens
at a very high level of the project, okay?
Oh, yeah.
Well, probably we can use the, once again,
the most used software in the engineering world,
which is paint.
So, let's use it so we can draw,
we can draw something in here, okay?
Okay, let's keep 100% for now.
Okay, great.
So, here we have the program approval, okay?
I'll mark it in red.
Here, guys, this is a very high level,
high management decision.
So, it's the management deciding,
okay, we are going to create,
to work on this project, okay?
I don't know, let's call it ST project, okay?
So, our card is the ST project, okay?
This is the project plan for the ST project, okay?
This is a fictional card.
Then, let's analyze some of these lines.
I would see, we will work on the spec freeze,
PCR fleet, eco,
and then this line starting from here onward,
this line onward, and stuff like this.
Let's start from the spec freeze.
The spec freeze is the moment
when a set of requirements are freeze, okay?
Frozen freeze, you pick the right way
to pronounce it or to say.
This means that, okay,
at this date, the 22nd of May,
we will have,
I'm just, you know, inventing numbers.
I don't remember the actual numbers,
but we will have,
let's put it, let's make it smaller.
We'll have like 25% of the requirements
will be ready,
and most of all,
they will be official, okay?
So, this means that 25% of the requirements are ready.
As you can see here,
there is a delta time
that passes from here to here, okay?
This time, this delta time, let's see,
is the time where once we know
that this program is going to happen,
then there will be a team
working on writing the requirements.
So, here, we will have
what is the up-left part of the V cycle,
the software requirement.
Do you remember the previous slide
where we had this first block
up-left side of the V cycle?
Here it is.
So, here, there will be a team
writing software requirement.
Of course, they will need some time
to write these requirements,
so they start writing the requirements,
and they will need one month,
two months, three months.
It depends on how much,
how many requirements we want to share
for this date, the 22 of May.
But then we will arrive that
the 22 of May,
the 0A release will be ready.
This means that 25% of the requirement
will be shared.
This is a timeline, okay?
Remember always to look both
to the timeline on the top part of the slide
and the timeline that we are working on here, okay?
As soon as we go on the right part of the slide,
we are advancing in time.
You see, there are also other releases
that we will have the 1A,
we will have the 2A,
but in general,
as your general understanding,
we will not have just three releases,
0A, 1A, and 2A.
In my experience,
I've seen 0A, 0B,
the 0C, 1A, and 2A.
These are five milestones,
let's say, for the requirements.
And you can understand that from 0A,
we will have the 25%,
I don't know, 0B, 50%,
0C, 75%,
1A, 100% of the requirements.
And then we will have another
and last release of the requirements
where we simply modify what was not working before
if we realize that there was something wrong
on the requirements.
So we will have a last release of the requirement,
that is the 2A.
As you see here,
there are no other phases after this 2A.
So this means that all the requirements
must be ready and finished
within the 2A.
After the 2A,
there will be no new requirements.
Of course, this is an ideal perspective,
let's say.
This is an ideal situation.
Quite likely in the likelihood of a project,
in the reality of the project,
it happens that we will have other requirements
in late phases of the project.
But this is an emergency case.
Most of the requirements should be closed
or at least 100% of the requirements
should be closed up and running,
let's say,
not modifiable,
from the 2A on.
The 2A is the last time
we can upload update requirements.
Okay.
But let's move back
to what we were saying before.
So when the requirements are released here,
let's say here we have
the software requirement release.
Okay.
Where the 25% of the requirements are written.
As you remember from the presentation
I was showing before,
so let's move back for one second.
Here you see the software requirements
is the first step.
Then there will be other steps.
These steps will be part of
the software development team.
So we will not see anything
that happens between
the release of the requirements
and the release of the first software.
The release of the first software,
in this case,
considering just ECHO1 timeline,
is this B100.
So as you see,
the B100 is released,
was released on 16th of September 2020,
while the requirements
were released 22th of May 2020.
So there were like four months
between the two releases.
What happened in these two months?
In these two months,
it happened that
the requirements were shared
with the software developers.
The software developers
discussed the requirements
with the specification engineer,
so the engineer
that wrote the requirement.
So there is a discussion
between the requirement engineer
and the software developers.
And once they agree on everything,
then the requirements are,
let's say, finalized.
So these requirements
are agreed between the parties.
And then the software developer team
starts to work on the requirement
and to actually implement them
in the software.
How?
First, creating a software architecture,
then a software design,
and finally constructing the software.
So the requirements are shared
and agreed between
the requirement engineer
and the software development team.
And finally,
the software development team
starts to work on them.
They create an architecture,
they design the software,
and they write the software.
Then they release the software.
So here we are simply
descending the left part
of the cycle, okay?
So this was the software requirement,
okay?
And here we start to go down the V
until we have the release
of the first software.
So they build the software
and then they give us,
so let's go down here for a while.
And then we start to raise the V,
okay?
Where we find the first part
that really matters
to us that are following
the validation program.
So remember,
this is the software requirement block.
Then we have the software architecture block.
We have the software design block.
Here we have the software construction.
And then we will have the,
let's see,
here at the phase of unit testing.
So here we will receive
the first software.
Where we upload this software,
so we have a bunch of lines of code,
okay?
But then we have to test this software.
So to test this software,
we will need a benchtop.
You will see different stuff
about these benchtops,
different kind of benchtops,
the car,
and stuff like this.
So hardware in the loop,
software in the loop,
whatever, okay?
There will be many strategies
to perform these tests.
But for the sake of this explanation,
we consider as an hypothesis
that before we received the software,
there was a team working
in preparing the benchtop for us,
okay?
This will be clearer
once you move forward
to the training program.
But for now,
let's consider that
we already have a benchtop
that is ready to be tested.
So we have a benchtop.
We have the electronic control unit one.
And when we receive the software
related to the electronic control unit one,
then we flash or upload the software
on the electronic control unit
and we start the test.
Question.
What kind of test do we start?
Guys, please remember always
that the starting point
and the full purpose
of the verification,
of the validation,
and in general,
the testing activities
is to make sure
that the software
and so the system
behaves
as the requirements
described,
okay?
This is the reason
why the requirements
are always
the most important phase,
okay?
They are extremely important
because they are the input document
for everything.
Whenever we have to test,
what we test
is that the software
behaves according
to the requirements,
okay?
Requirements must enter
in your head.
I don't know
if you want to
tattoo
these requirements
on your heart.
You want to write
requirements everywhere
on your copybook,
wherever,
put as a screen saver
on your computer.
What is extremely important
is that you remember
that the input
of all,
all,
all the activities
that you will see here
in this company
starts from
the requirements,
okay?
So,
this is actually,
again,
an experience
that I had.
So,
I was working
on this project
when I received
B100 software.
There was another team
working on a benchtop.
This team provided me
the benchtop.
I had the electronic
control unit one.
I flashed the software
and I had
to make sure
that the software
behaved according
to the 25%
of the requirements
that were shared
on the zero errorings,
okay?
So,
we have
a bunch of requirements
and we make sure
that these requirements
are properly implemented
in the software,
okay?
As you see here,
there is a similarities
in colors,
okay?
So,
this light blue
is the same light blue
that we have
on all these points,
okay?
I'm just focusing
on the development
of ECO1,
but as you've already
seen in the introduction
videos about
the e-architecture
or generally
of all the electronic
control units
that you have
on a car,
you may realize
that there are
like 30,
40,
50 electronic
control units
inside the car.
So,
what we say
for one electronic
control unit
may apply also
for other 30,
40,
or 50 electronic
control units.
We have requirements
that are related
to the bull car,
so it means
that these requirements
to be properly
implemented
need the collaboration
of many electronic
control units
or some requirements
that are specific
for one electronic
control unit.
But anyway,
we will
deep this
topic
in further
lessons.
So,
we arrived
at the unit test
phase.
Okay,
do you remember
we are here?
Why unit test?
Especially
for the first
part of the project,
you do not
have
a
system
that looks
like the final
product.
So,
basically,
we do not
have a car.
have a very
advanced
hardware in the
loop that
simulate the car
because we are
at the beginning
of the project.
So,
at the beginning
of the project,
here,
we just focus
on one
electronic
control unit.
This is why
here we mentioned
the unit test,
which is focusing
on testing
just our
component.
So,
here,
most of the time,
we have
a simplified
hardware in the
loop where there
is an ideal
and simplified
model of a car,
the only
available hardware
is our
electronic control
unit and we
work only
with the
electronic control
unit 1,
testing the
software B100.
You see here
there are many
other software,
B110,
B120,
and stuff like
this.
This can be
both because
the 0A
requirements
couldn't be
implemented
fully in
B100 and
maybe they
splitted part
in B100,
part in B110
and other
part of B120,
but also because
once we start
testing,
we can have
problems and
we will see
what happens
in that case.
Let's focus on
something very
important that
is up here.
So,
I slightly
delete this
part because
I want to
focus on
this timeline,
this one.
this is the
timeline of
the vehicles.
Let's
explain this
better.
Where you
see here
Mule 1,
Mule 1 is
the first
prototype ever
of that
project.
This is a
car that is
built by hand
basically.
Okay?
So,
parts of
other cars
are taken,
they're put,
they're all
together,
they're put
and we
create
first
prototype.
Is this
just a
random
prototype?
No.
Probably
10% of
this car
will be
what we
will find
in the
final product,
while the
90% of
the car
is something
different.
So,
the purpose
here is
just to
test the
10% of
the car
that will
be actually
part of
the final
product.
Why I'm
focusing on
this?
I'm focusing
on this
because this
means that
before this
16th of
November,
before,
there are
no cars.
Okay?
So,
we are
working on
a project
to create
a car,
to work
on this
car that
we call
ST
project,
but before
16th of
November,
if everything
goes according
to the
plan,
we have
no car.
So,
this explains
you why
we focus
first on
unit test
because at
the beginning
it's extremely
important first
to test that
the single
unit works
properly.
Then,
once we
move in
the timeline,
we will
have other
electronic
control unit,
let's say
in a way
debugged,
or at least
other components
that start
to be more
mature,
and we can
move to
the next
phase of
the system
testing,
okay?
The integration
testing,
sorry.
So,
we don't
have just
the test
of one
component,
but then
we start
to put
together
more
electronic
control
units.
This is
needed because,
as I was
mentioning
before,
the requirements
are the
feature that
we have on
cars,
most of
them imply
the collaboration
of more
than one
electronic
control unit.
I always
do the
example of
the cruise
control,
or for
example,
the adaptive
cruise control.
The adaptive
cruise control
is a feature
that allows
you to
follow a
car without
just braking
or accelerating.
The car
will do
everything by
itself.
In order
to do
that,
the car
needs to
read information
from the
radar,
camera,
and then
accelerate
by itself,
brake by
itself.
So,
all these
devices are
not controlled
just by one
electronic
control unit,
but there
are more
than one,
there are
two,
three,
four,
five electronic
control units
working to
make the
adaptive cruise
control working
properly in
the car.
So,
it's okay
that I have
the single
electronic control
unit working
properly,
but then,
in order to
make this
feature working
properly also
on a car,
so that actually
a driver can
use an adaptive
cruise control,
it's extremely
important that
not just the
unit works,
but that also
the different
units participating
with this
feature talk
properly to
each other
and make
sure that the
adaptive cruise
control will
work properly
on a car.
So,
before we
arrive to
the testing
phase in
the car,
we perform
first unit
test,
then integration
so we start
to put together
the electronic
control units
and see what
happens when
they talk to
each other
and if they
talk properly
to each
other,
and finally,
we arrive to
the last
phase,
okay,
now this
V is a bit
weird,
let's say
it's something
like this,
we arrive to
the last
phase here,
that is
the new
one,
so here
finally we
have the
first car,
on a car
we do not
focus only
on the
single unit,
but we
focus on the
whole system
performing
functional
tests,
so now
we see that
there is a
connection
between this
V cycle
that is
on a slide
and a
V cycle
seen on
a real
project,
okay,
so let's
see if I
can
clean a
bit the
mess that
I created
over here,
maybe it's
better just
to move
here directly,
so we're
at this
point,
here you
see we
have the
first V
cycle
drawn on
a real
project
plan
card,
so I
have a
look at
this
slide
for a
while,
okay,
this is the
final slide,
so you
see that
V cycle
repeats
itself
many,
many times,
okay,
this is just
a qualitative
expression,
okay,
this doesn't
mean that
we have
I don't
know,
I drawn
just
6 V
cycles,
but V
cycle
repeats
itself
over and
over
again,
why,
because I
received
the B100,
then I
start
testing,
let's
say I
start
testing
something
in
Mule 1,
which is
the first
prototype or
even while
testing in
my electronic
control unit,
in the unit
test,
I realized
there is
something wrong,
there might be
something wrong
on the requirements,
there could be
something wrong
on the
software side,
and stuff like
this,
but if
something is
not working,
which means
if the
software and
the system
are not
behaving as
the requirement
expects,
then I
raise an
issue,
saying,
okay,
there is an
issue with
the system,
the issue
is analyzed
by,
first of
all,
by us,
so we
perform a
first analysis,
and then,
or someone
will help us,
and then if
it's a
software
requirement,
then the
software must
be modified,
so again,
could be an
architectural
problem,
a design
or simply
a one-line
code problem,
the software
is modified,
and then a
new version
of the software
is released,
so we will
have another,
let's say,
V cycle,
but this time,
this line of
the unit test
will not pass
through the
B100,
but will pass
for B110.
so every
time you
have a
software release,
there will
be a
V cycle,
okay,
or again,
in case the
problem were
the requirements,
because there
was something
not clear,
or a requirement
was not
properly written,
then the
V cycle
repeats itself,
and requirements
are modified,
eventually there
is a 0B
release,
as we were
mentioning before,
so an updated
version of the
requirements,
a new
software is
developed,
and then a
new software
is released,
and we keep
testing the
requirements,
okay,
so we start
testing activities,
still trying
to make sure
that the
software,
and then the
system,
behaves according
to the
requirements,
okay,
so the
V cycle
repeats itself
many,
many times,
okay,
so just keep
in mind that
this is a
process that
you will
always work
with,
okay,
let's go
back to
this picture,
so we were
focusing here
on this
timeline,
we have just
mentioned the
new one,
this is just
an invented
number,
okay,
this is not
actually true,
but let's
see that on
the new one,
10% of the
car is
the,
what we will
actually find,
and the
final project,
so the
car that
is actually
sold to
people,
while 90%
is something
else.
As we move
on on the
timeline,
so moving
on on the
timeline,
it means that
the software
is,
every time
there is a
software release,
the software
is better,
is more
complete,
we are testing
that the
software complies
with the
requirements,
there is also
another release
of the
requirements,
so it means
that having
a new set
of requirements,
we will have
a software
which will
contain more
requirements and
stuff like this,
okay,
so we
are getting,
as soon as we
move on the
right side,
a better software
or a more
complete software,
then we will
arrive to the
face of the
Mule 2,
the Mule 2,
and once again,
here guys,
I'm inventing
these numbers,
okay,
so I'm not sure
it's like this,
something around
this,
but yeah,
Mule 2 is still
a prototype,
but in this
case we will
have that 50%
of the car
is actually
the car
that we will
find on the
market,
while the
other 50%
is something
else,
please keep
in mind
that the
Mule 1
is the
first actual
car for
that project,
so it means
that you
have one
car,
okay,
then Mule 2,
since it is
similar to
the final
product,
it makes
sense to
have more
than one
Mule,
one than
more car,
so that we
can start
performing
some tests,
okay,
keep in mind
that it's
very helpful
and easy
to work
on an
HIL,
because,
so an
hardware in
the loop,
because we
have just
one real
hardware,
which is the
electronic
control unit
that we
are testing,
but then
everything
that is
around the
electronic
control unit
is just
a model,
is ideal,
so there
are some
situations
that we
cannot test
or some
problems
that we
could not
realize and
understand
testing it
from the
hardware in
the loop,
but then
that will
be clear
if we
test it
in the
car,
okay,
so guys,
in the
past,
all the
tests were
done on
prototypes,
okay,
in the past
when the
car were
mechanical
and all
of this
software
stuff was
not
reality,
everything
was done
using these
prototypes,
but prototypes
are very
expensive to
be done,
it's very
slow
activities,
if you
break a
prototype,
then to
have another
one,
it takes
weeks,
so it's
very slow
and very
expensive,
so in
order to
save money,
we are
trying to
push
everything,
to do
everything that
is possible
on a
hardware in
the loop,
which is,
let's say,
easy to
configure it,
replace,
easy to
improve and
stuff like
this,
or not
easy in
itself,
but easier
than having
a car,
okay,
and for
sure,
less expensive
and much
faster.
Again,
once we
move on,
we have
another
development
of the
car,
we arrive
at the
BP,
which is,
which are
the vehicle
production,
here,
once again,
let's say,
we have
that 80%
of the
car is
what we
will actually
find on
the market,
and 20%
is still
something else,
okay,
so there are
still some
parts that
will be
not really
part of
the final
project.
Vehicle
production
phase,
maybe even
85%,
okay,
so it
means that
this car
is actually
very close
to the
final one.
Once we
have a
car that
is so
close to
the final
one,
this means
that performing
tests on
this car
will be
extremely
helpful,
because it
will help
us to
understand
if everything
is working,
not just
in a
laboratory
or using
a simulator,
but also
using actually
the car
in the
street.
PS is the
pre-series
car, so
here, let's
say that
95%
of the
car or
even
98%
of the
car is
the car
that we
will have
at the
end.
PRA
is, let's
say, here
we have
that actual
cars are
already
delivered to
the management
of the
client, just
to see
how a
car is
actually
performing
used by
a normal
driver, so
a driver that
is not
technician, but
a normal
person having
the car, and
finally, if
everything is
going well, then
we will
arrive to
this phase, which
is the most
important phase, the
one that we
always look at,
which is, in
this case, called
job one.
Job one is
the day when
the production
starts, the
production, in
series, of
the car
starts.
this is a
name that
is used by
a specific
client, there
are other
clients that
call it in a
different way, for
example, simply
SOP, start
of production, or
simply production, or
deliver, final
delivery, whatever,
there are all
kind of names for
this phase, but
what is extremely
important for you
is that you
have always
in mind, where
is this job
one, when
one, and
when are the
main milestone
of the
project, so
that you
know when
the project is
going to
finish, and
when the
car is
actually sold.
So it
means that
from the
job one
on worth, the
car started
to be produced
and sold
on the
market.
The
suggestion
here, so
is always to
have in
mind big
picture of
the project,
okay, when
you will
start working,
okay, now
it's very
soon, because
you have
just, you
know, probably
the second
day of the
company, when
you are
watching this
video, you
will know, you
will have no
idea of what
you are going
to do in
the activities,
but this is a
suggestion that
I give at
every stage of
the career, one
person, when it
starts, or even
when they're
an expert or
senior profiling
the company,
have always a
big picture of
what is going
on here,
okay.
A work could
become very
abstract, I
mean, during
this validation
training, you
will see a
huge focus on
variables, on
the bit, this
bit goes to
one, this bit
goes to zero,
the variable
goes to
three, this
will go to
50 and
stuff like
so, things
that looks
like abstract
with no
physical meaning,
but this is
actually the
contrary, because
everything you're
going to do
is going to
affect the
volt vehicle, so
always ask
yourself, okay,
what is going
to happen if I
do something on
the software,
what is going
to happen on
the high level
point of view,
because it
will have a
general effect
on a car, and
so will affect
also this
plan, okay.
So, always
looking at the
plan, as you
see here,
here, there
are these
signs, okay,
this is the
symbol of
ice, this is
the symbol of
sun, and
here you have
them again.
These are
symbols of
the winter
tests that are
done on the
snow, and
these are the
summer tests
usually done in
the desert or
extremely hot
countries.
So, having in
mind that this
is going to
happen, so
in this
moment, in
this period of
the year, there
will be winter
tests, I will
make sure that
even though, even
if the software
is not, you
know, we are
still working on
B200 series,
okay, so we are
implementing the
1A requirements,
so we will have
also another
release of
requirements,
there will be a
lot of other
software in the
future, so we
know that the
software is not
still the best
and the perfect
one, but I
will, I know
that these two
weeks, there
will be people
working in a
car on the
snow, so I
will have to
give the
highest priority
to all the
activities that
are related to
the management
of, I don't
know, the
ether of the
battery packs.
the battery
pack will
work in
a specific
temperature range
and they need
to have the
batteries always
working at that
temperature range,
so if the
ether is not
working, either
the battery pack
will stop working
so the electric
vehicle will be,
will stuck, or
even the
air conditioner, I
mean, let's
consider people
working at minus
10 degrees,
probably they
will get
frozen if
they don't
have the
air conditioner
or the
ether working
properly, so
this is
probably the
contents to
verify, to
test, will
be a lot,
so among
all the tests
that you have
to do, having
a big picture
of the project
will help you
to give the
right priority
of the stuff,
and here we
are always
talking about
the VOOCYCLE,
you know, we
have not changed
the topic, because
again, the VOOCYCLE
is something like
this, then we
will have another
requirements here,
so we will
have something like
this, and
arriving to the
move 2, and
so on, okay, so
what I'm trying
to say here is
that this is an
actual plan where
you can actually
apply the
concepts that
you got from
the VOOCYCLE
lesson, okay,
these are the
winter tests, these
are the summer
tests, and then
we will repeat
them once the
everything is
clearer, not
clearer, but the
software is more
mature, we have
the VOOCYCLE
cars, so it's
much more
meaningful to
perform tests on
these kind of
cars and
softwares, because
the project is
almost at the
end, so it
means that
everything is,
let's say,
almost already
working properly,
okay,
keep looking at
the slide, there
are so many
things that we
could mention,
one of the, so
we have, let's
say, described
this timeline
about cars,
related to the
VOOCYCLE that
are called
Quality
Gate, I will
not really go
into details
about it, because
this is, let's
say, an
advanced content,
so we are going
to review this
slide further in
the future, what
is important
here is to
describe the
PCR fleet
thing, okay,
this is the
PCR fleet
timeline, so the
VOOCYCLE that
we mentioned
before, it
applies, as I
was saying, not
just on one
electronic control
unit, but this
process applies to
all the electronic
control units, so
there will be, I
don't know, we
have 50
electronic control
units, we will
have 50 VOOCYCLE
in parallel going
on, but of
course, the car
that we are
working on is
just one, okay,
so the system, we
are actually
debugging and
the system on
which we are
improving the
quality, because
let's move back
here, if you
see the VOOCYCLE,
the left part is
the software
development part,
but then the
right part is the
quality assurance,
and as you see, as
we move on the
right side, we
move from unit
test to the
functional test,
we are basically
improving the
quality of the
system, okay, so
even though we
have 50 small
systems, and 50
teams, for
example, working
on these different
electronic control
units, then there
must be some
common points
where all these
electronic control
units, all this
work come together
and put on the
car, everything
works, this is
actually what a
PCR is, PCR
is basically a
release of a
group of
software that
put all
together on a
car will be
able to
properly
implement
everything that
is listed, in
this case, in
0A
requirements, so
specification,
release.
Once again, you
see the
color that are
similar, okay?
So this means that
1A will implement
everything that is
being described in
0A, the 2A
PCR release will
implement everything
that has been
defined in 1A, and
stuff like this.
of course, we
have only 2A as
a final release of
the requirements, but
we will have more
than one, so more
than the 2A
release, we have
the 3A, 4A, 5A, 6A,
and stuff like this.
We will go deeper
into details about
this slide once we
will get to the
right topic, but
what you have to
know is that once
we put everything on
a car, car is a
very complex system
where there are a
lot, lot of
systems talking to
each other,
collaborating, and
working to make
sure that one
feature works
properly.
Once again, we
can do the
example of the
adaptive cruise
control.
The adaptive cruise
control works
using the work
of many teams
that have worked
on the
powertrain
electronic control
unit, battery
pack control
unit, ADAS
electronic control
unit, all this
stuff.
So when the
1A release of
PCR happens, it
means that all
the suppliers
have to provide
a software that
once put in a
car, is able to
make on a car
this feature
working.
So it means that
the brake has to
properly talk to
the powertrain
electronic control
unit.
They both have to
talk to the
battery pack.
Everything has to
talk with the
ADAS.
ADAS has to
send all the
information in the
right time to the
other electronic
control unit.
So all these
echoes must work
properly together
and all these
echoes must have
specific software
to make this
feature working
properly on a
car.
Okay.
And this happens
every time.
This is 1A, 2A,
3A, 4A, 5A,
6A.
So as we move
on the right
side of the
project, we are
advancing.
We are advancing
on the timeline.
And this means
that everything
will be...
So in 1A,
part of the car
will work,
2A, we have
more contents
working,
3A, the car
works quite
well, 4A, we
have almost
everything we
have just to
tune parameters,
5A is just
looking forward
to the production,
6A is the
final release
where everything
has to work
properly.
final words
about this
slide.
Well, we
can...
We could
keep describing
what are
these, you
know, rectangles
here, the
purple one, the
green one, blue
one, the
orange one.
Okay.
So there are a
lot of things
that we could
mention, but
the general and
final suggestion
that I would
give you, and I
already gave you
before, so it's
just repetition.
Every time you
perform an
activity, please
have in mind the
general idea of
the project, the
general timing of
the project.
These documents,
if you work on
this, on a
specific client,
you will actually
find this kind of
layout, because it's
still used, okay,
for projects of
2023, 2024,
2025.
So you will
see still this
kind of
layout.
But even other
clients, other
care makers,
whoever, there is
always, always a
general plan of
the project we are
working on.
So the
suggestion here is
do not just
focus on your
specific activity,
just looking at
your screen and
thinking only on
your test to be
executed, but
always ask to
you're responsible.
Can I have a
general overview of
the timing of the
project I'm working
on?
I know that these
things looks like
obvious for you
right now, but I'm
sure, and I've seen
so many people going
through this program
and then start
working.
Then once you start
working, you are so
overwhelmed by
technical thing that
you have to learn,
the deadline to meet
and stuff like this
that you will
completely forget to
have a general
perspective of the
project.
But just take your
time and remember
having a general
perspective of the
project will help
you very much to
focus on what is a
real priority in that
period and what is
not, why an
activity has to be
done in one week
and why another
activity has to be
done in three weeks
and stuff like this.
okay, so just to
close with the
proper slide and
not just the screen
that I was doing,
it's very, very
important that we
do not just think
of the cycle as
this draw on a
slide that is,
okay, very easy to
understand, but
extremely far from
the daily life
activities.
This is not true
true at all because
the VOOCYCLE will
also apply on
real case project
card, project plan
here, and you can
see this VOOCYCLE
repeating itself over
and over again
until the project
gets to the final
part, which is the
production.
Please remember
that, okay, that we
are debugging the
software, so we are
making sure that the
software works
properly, but the
final goal is to
sell cars that
behave properly.
Consider always
yourself in a car
and think, okay,
would I like this
behavior of the
car?
Would I like that
while I'm driving on
a highway, something
goes wrong and the
car doesn't realize
anything?
Would I like that I
have to spend like
5,000 hero just to
understand a small
problem that could
have been very clear
if I had done the
proper testing phase?
So ask always these
questions, put yourself
in the car and have
always a big
perspective view on
the activities that
you are doing.
VOOCYCLE is just,
it's not just a V
drawn on a paper,
it's a process that
we actually follow on
a daily basis.